# Abhisek Pahadi

Email ID: abhisekpahadi@gmail.com

Contact Number: +91- 9438712410

#### Summary

A goal-oriented HR professional with experience in business partnering and leading large OD Initiatives, PMS, HR transformation and Change management projects in organization across Consulting, IT/ITES & banking industry. A change agent striving to enable an engaged work force aligned to business vision. A technology enthusiast with a constant focus on leveraging HR capabilities

Key Skills		
Performance Management	Organizational Development	Stakeholder Management
Talent Management	Career Development Programs	Manpower Planning
Employee Engagement	Succession Planning	Talent Analytics
Work Experience (10 Years)		
ITC Limited – Hotels Division	Manager	May 24 – Present
KPMG Global Services	Manager	Mar 21 – Apr 24
Infosys Limited	Senior Associate Lead - OD	Mar 18 – Mar 21
ICICI Bank	Management Trainee	May 17 – Mar 18
Infosys Limited	Test Engineer	May 13 – Jun 15
ITC Limited – Hotels Division	1	May 2024 - Present

- Collaborate with business heads to manage people program, resolve employee issues for the function
- Manage performance management system for the managerial cadre employees
- Redefine the overall performance system framework with inception of continuous feedback, check-in and rolebased goal setting
- Design the competency framework for 3 functions in the division and curate the talent readiness program
- Introduce Assessment Centre to create the succession pipeline for leadership roles
- Define and execute the quarterly variable pay program for managers
- Enhance the benefit program for managers with introduction of curated offerings for hospitality industry employees
- Strategize the compensation philosophy, conduct the benchmarking exercise and execute the annual compensation review program
- Partner with business leaders to create the sales incentive structure, target linked rewards program for the front
  office roles in the hotels
- Oversee the employee engagement survey, analyze the outcomes and design long term solutions to meet employee aspirations
- Automate employee dashboards for assessing employee details, attrition analysis and employee aspiration trends

#### **KPMG Global Services (Manager)**

Mar 2021 - Apr 2024

- Partner with business to design and execute the people agenda aligned to business strategy
- Design the career architecture, skill matrix and growth readiness framework for all business units
- Create talent mobility framework and platform for employees to pursue career opportunity within the organization
- Built a mechanism to leverage skills repository to enable employees to work on aspired engagements, upskill via gamification
- Institutionalize a consistent approach for succession planning across business units
- Define the ideal span of control and organization pyramid through industry benchmarking
- Design compensation strategy, benchmarking exercise and the bonus payout structure for the business unit
- Devise Engagement framework for employees to enable work satisfaction

- Manage Performance Appraisal for the unit of 2000 employees
- Automate the early attrition warning system for easy governance and process enhancement

## Infosys Limited (Senior Associate Lead – OD)

Mar 2018 – Mar 2021

### **Performance Management**

- Defined new performance management philosophy moving from compliance based approach to social and employee development focused approach
- Led the project of integrating performance management system with MS-Team to enable accessibility, induce usability and leverage the power of continuous feedback
- Introduced the concept of Team based performance management system for Project Management roles
- Integrated developmental goals with LMS to enable skill growth
- Implemented the alignment of project management goals with performance management system to streamline goal setting process
- Automated the KPIs for monthly and quarterly performance scorecard for leaders
- Collaborated with business leaders and HRBPs to drive the performance management exercise which involves goal setting, performance conversation, feedback and audit of the ratings
- Handled Performance Related Consequence Management activities such as PIP, Performance Warning Letter

### **Talent Management and Development**

- Partnered with business to drive promotion and progression exercise for the business unit
- Designed career navigator framework for employees through reskilling and refactoring
- Introduced the concept of Check In performance and career development conversations of employees with managers
- Defined the inter stream role mobility through skill enhancement and role clustering
- Collaborated with L&D team to gamify the skill trajectory for the digital career stream
- Identified critical roles as part of succession planning, conducted the talent review meetings, enabled Individual development plan for future leaders
- Worked on identifying HiPos in the organization through people factor and situation factor
- Created Employee Aspiration Matrix and Governance structure for their fulfillment through stakeholder partnership

## **Analytics and Reporting**

- Automated the offline employee related reports to live reports based on Power BI implementation
- Worked on a Predictive attrition model to identify high risk employees to enable meaningful discussion with critical talents

#### **Employee Engagement**

- Planning, deploying and analysis of Employee engagement survey to understand the PULSE on the ground
- Introduced a new engagement framework based on Start, continue and stop methodology in collaboration with business leaders

## **ICICI Bank (Management Trainee)**

May 2017 – Mar 2018

- Managed Employee Relations for more than 2000 employees in Rest of Maharashtra zone
- Conducted Manpower Planning for Retail Business Group based on productivity and business prospect
- Championed Employee Benefit policies and proficient use of PEOPLESOFT to manage manpower related transactions
- Automation of the transfer module to reduce the dependency on manual transactions related to personal transfer requests
- Drove the 360 degree feedback mechanism and initiated leadership potential assessment for employees in middle management and senior management roles
- Implemented Labor Law compliance in all the operational branches in rest of Maharashtra zone
- Ensured resource alignment (Internal) through identification of manpower for key roles

## **Infosys Limited (Test Engineer)**

May 2013 – Jun 2015

- Design Engineer- Devised the automated testing framework for a completely new application resulting in effort saving of around 200 hours
- Quality Analyst- Assessed the quality of testing related documents such as test strategy, test plan and assured it to be of highest quality deliverables thereby reducing the testing time by 50 hours per release
- Business Consultant Coordinated with clients and onsite team members for understanding the business requirements and providing strategic solutions to them
- Module Lead Mentored the new employees in the team and made them aware of the business needs and technological aspects of the application

## **Accenture Limited (Summer Intern)**

Apr 2016 – May 2016

- Established a structured DMSP framework and enabled strong alignment between Recruitment Delivery
   Sourcing team
- Enabled effective sourcing channel utilization by proper channel mix
- Created SLA (Service Level Agreement) based reporting mechanism
- Transformed offline mechanism of demand movement tracking to online mode

## **Educational Qualifications**

#### **Xavier Institute of Management, Bhubaneswar**

MBA in Human Resource Management (CGPA – 7.47)

June 2015 - Mar 2017

## **National Institute of Science and Technology**

B.Tech. in Electrical and Electronics Engineering (CGPA – 8.11)

Aug 2008 – June 2012

#### Certifications

- AON Certified Distinguished Talent Management Professional in the year 2024
- Achieved the Business English Certification Vantage, University of Cambridge ESOL examination, in the year 2010
- "Managerial Competencies for an HR Manager" by Mr. KJA Swarup, General Manager at ITC Ltd.
- "Managing Change" by Mr. Mirza Yawar Baig, Yawar Baig & Associates

#### **Awards**

- Above and Beyond Award for HR excellence award at KGS
- KUDOS award for being trusted partner at KGS
- ACE Award for creating high value impact for business in 2019 amongst all HR teams in Infosys
- INSTA Award in driving Attrition reduction at the current unit in Infosys IDEATOR Award at Organization Level for creating talent segmentation and aspiration matrix for the unit
- Unit Special Award in for driving PMS activity at the unit with minimum employee concern